Guide to the Daniel Edwards Kennedy Collection
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
Daniel Edwards Kennedy collection
1799-1931
1893-1931
YCAL MSS 588
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
0.63
(2 boxes)
Contains autograph manuscripts of Kennedy's writings and autograph letters, signed, from various individuals to Kennedy. Also includes manuscript and printed material relating to The Queen's Shop, Kennedy's private press and bindery, and other papers. The papers date from 1799 to 1931.
Kennedy, Daniel Edwards
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Roger Stoddard, 1967.
Conditions Governing Access
The materials are open for research.
Daniel Edwards Kennedy (1879-1960)
Daniel Edwards Kennedy, American writer. Kennedy owned The Queen's Shop, a private press and bindery in Chestnut Hill and Brookline, MA. He graduated from Yale University in 1903.
Scope and Contents
Contains autograph manuscripts of Kennedy's writings and autograph letters, signed, from various individuals to Kennedy. Also includes manuscript and printed material relating to The Queen's Shop, Kennedy's private press and bindery, and other papers. The papers date from 1799 to 1931.
Arrangement
Organized into three series: I. Writings, 1894-1907. II. Correspondence, 1799-1931. III. Other Papers, 1893-1926.
American literature -- 20th Century; Authors, American -- 20th Century; Printers -- United States; Authors -- United States -- 20th Century; Printers -- United States -- 20th Century; Kennedy, Daniel Edwards; Queen's Shop
- Writings, 1894-1907, undated; Series I; 24
  Arrangement
  Arranged alphabetically by writing title.
  Scope and Contents
  All writings are autograph manuscripts unless otherwise noted.
  - "The Bear Who Talks", undated (Box 1)
  - "Bibliodaemon" autograph and typescript drafts, undated (Box 1)
  - "College Rhetoric", 1901 (Box 1)
  - "Critchett's Cat", undated (Box 1)
  - "The Cynic" autograph draft and printed version, undated (Box 1)
  - "An Episode of Trump Life" autograph and typescript drafts, undated (Box 1)
  - "Flowers from the Blue Hills", undated (Box 1)
  - Golf: in Sapphira's Days, proof copy, 1910 (Box 1)
  - Granite State Magazine, printed version containing "Thoreau in Old Dunstable", 1907 December (Box 1)
  - "In a Turkish Corner", undated (Box 1)
  - "The Lady I Rode With" autograph and typescript drafts, undated (Box 1)
  - "Lover Monks" autograph and typescript drafts, undated (Box 1)
  - "Marbouchais", undated (Box 1)
  - "My Best Model" autograph and typescript drafts, undated (Box 1)
  - An Old Oak Table and Others, printed version, 1897 (Box 1)
  - "The Scholar in the Library", undated (Box 1)
  - "The Strenuous Spinster", undated (Box 1)
  - "The Times That Try Men's Souls", undated (Box 1)
  - "Twenty Pairs of Spectacles", undated (Box 1)
  - The Voice from New York, nine printed versions, 1894 April-1896 June (Box 1)
  - "Walking", undated (Box 1)
  - "The Witch of the White Mountains", undated (Box 1)
  - Various fragments and unidentified drafts, undated (Box 1)
  - Poems by Irvine Goddard, undated (Box 1)
- Correspondence, 1799-1931; Series II; 3
  Contains letters from various correspondents to Kennedy.
  - Dwight, Theodore, 1799, 1801, 1806 (Box 1)
  - Elliott, Zo, 1918 (Box 1)
    Includes clippings
  - Lewis, Sinclair, 1931 (Box 1)
- Other Papers, 1893-1926, undated; Series II; 9
  - Manuscript and printed material relating to The Queen's Shop, including accounts and correspondence relating to the operation and its sale., 1893-1918; 6 (Box 2)
  - Material relating to the Yale Pundits, 1903-1906 (Box 2)
  - Subscription forms for Philip the Forester: A Romance of the Valley of Gardens by Daniel Edward Kennedy, 1908 (Box 2)
  - Miscellaneous clippings, 1926, undated (Box 2)